DNA sequencing machines produce large amount of "reads".
Each of them originates from a certain genome location.
If we analyse a known organism, we can
compare the new data to a reference genome.
We will now show how to find where
each query read aligns in a reference.
We will use the A* shortest path
algorithm to find optimal alignments very efficiently.
To direct the A-star search, we will
first divide the read into short seeds.
We will now match each seed to all its exact occurences and
mark the preceding reference positions with what we call bread crumbs. These
crumbs will prove handy when we will want to know how promising
a certain direction is for bringing us to a best alignment.
In order to give the possibility to start our search from one
place, we will aggregate the the whole reference into a trie index.